MICHAEL HUGHES

407-637-4302 hughescoding@gmail.co m

607 Pheasant Ave Longwood, FL 32751

Profile

I am currently an IT Director, Trainer and USMC veteran with 20 years experience working professionally in technology. I'm also now a full stack developer and graduate of the UCF coding bootcamp. In this 24 week course I developed with HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node, and more.

I have a passion for technology integration and am a tireless learner of all things tech. I have seen the transformative role technology plays in people's lives and am excited to leverage new solutions and use them to improve things we do.

I have experience building networks, servers and systems. In my career and personal life I have learned and mastered many complex technical systems and always look forward to the challenge of something new. Currently I am the IT director of a private school. One of my many accomplishments there was starting the schools first Makerspace and starting a coding programing for elementary and middle school students.

I hope to utilize my interpersonal skills and technological can-do attitude as I join a web development team and build upon the skills I learned in the UCF full stack development program.

Experience

IT Director, Jewish Academy of Orlando; Maitland, FL — 2011-Present Technology leader. Responsible for technology planning, procurement, deployment, management and support for entire organization. Maintain donor relationships to help fund technology initiatives. Lead web and CMS implementation and management. Develop and deliver training to staff on organizational technology platforms. Provide instruction on technology, coding & robots to grades 3 thru 5. Created schools maker space. Technical Lead and program oversight for our news studio daily news broadcast. Go-To guru for all things technology.

District Technology Coordinator, Silvis Schools, Silvis, IL — 2009-2011
Research and recommend technology solutions to achieve district goals.
Responsible for maintenance and support of district technology assets. Managed student information system. Implemented Activboard interactive whiteboards for classrooms. Provided technology training to staff. Wrote district technology plan.

Technology Consultant, M R Hughes Consulting, Moline, IL — 2006-2009 Designed, Sold and Deployed networks for clients. Provided server support and configuration for clients. Developed business relationships. Provided outsourced IT to clients. Provided remote & onsite administration to client network and server systems.

Senior Apple Systems Engineer, IRDG, Davenport, IA — 2003-2006

Member of Apple Consultants Network. Subcontracted service to Apple Computer providing on-site technical services to Apple education customers. Supervised inhouse software development team. Mentored junior Apple systems engineers. Developed and maintained business relationships. Conceptualized, planned and hosted educational technology conference hosting 200+ schools.

Education

University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida — Coding Bootcamp Certificate, 2018-19

American Institute of Commerce, Davenport, IA — Network Engineer Course, 1998-99

United States Marine Corps, Twentynine Palms, CA — 1993-97

Skills

Problem Solving, Trouble-shooting, Interpersonal soft skills, Growth Mindset, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL, Node, React, Git, Github, Word Press, Joomla, Visual Studio Code, G-suite, Google, Apple, MS Office, Networking, Management.

References

Available upon request